The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation, or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: OK, so up until now, we've
教授：好的，到目前为止，我们已经
been talking about the shortest path in graphs.
一直在谈论图形中的最短路径。
And we've been talking about these game problems
我们一直在谈论这些游戏问题
where you came up with a way to represent the state of a game
您想出了一种表示游戏状态的方法
as noting graphs.
作为图表。
And then we drew edges between those vertices that represented
然后我们在代表这些顶点的那些顶点之间绘制边缘
states, to represent moves that you can do in a game.
状态，以表示您可以在游戏中进行的移动。
It turns out you can solve a lot of problems this way.
事实证明，您可以通过这种方式解决很多问题。
And you can do it without thinking of a graph at all.
而且，您完全不需要考虑图表就可以做到。
So we usually think of a graph, build the graph,
所以我们通常想到一个图，建立一个图，
then run dynamic programming.
然后运行动态编程。
You can do better without building the graph.
您可以在不构建图表的情况下做得更好。
And the good part about that is that your code is smaller,
好处是您的代码较小，
and it runs faster.
而且运行速度更快。
The bad part about that is it's harder to understand.
不好的部分是很难理解。
The dynamic programming code looks like black magic.
动态编程代码看起来像黑魔法。
And, when we're going to give you dynamic programming
而且，当我们要为您提供动态编程时
problems on the final, you can't say, oh,
决赛中的问题，你不能说，哦，
we're going to build something and run [? dystring ?].
我们将要构建一些东西并运行[？ dystring？]。
And get partial credit.
并获得部分信用。
You actually have to understand the magic,
您实际上必须了解魔术，
and write the formulas, and hopefully get
并写出公式，并希望得到
something that works.
有用的东西。
So, we're going to spend all the time that we have left
因此，我们将花所有剩下的时间
in the semester, I think, building up
我认为在这个学期中
your intuition for how to build dynamic programming.
您对如何构建动态编程的直觉。
So, from lecture, dynamic programming
因此，从讲座开始，动态编程
is just a catchy name for for optimization problems.
只是优化问题的易记名称。
So, problems where you're trying to compute
因此，您尝试计算的问题
the minimum or the maximum of something.
最小或最大的东西。
So let's start with a problem.
因此，让我们从一个问题开始。
And then, see how all the concepts in lecture
然后，看看讲座中的所有概念
relate to that.
与此有关。
So this problem is called Crazy Eights.
因此，这个问题称为“疯狂八人”。
And we start out with a deck of cards, randomly shuffled.
我们从随机洗牌的一副纸牌开始。
And then some of the cards are pulled out.
然后将其中一些卡拔出。
Did everyone see playing cards?
大家都看过扑克牌吗？
Poker cards?
扑克牌？
Does everyone know what they are or do I have to define them?
每个人都知道它们是什么还是我必须定义它们？
Does anyone need me to define poker cards?
有人需要我定义扑克牌吗？
Let's put it that way.
让我们这样说。
OK.
好。
Cool.
凉。
So, suppose we have a bunch of these.
因此，假设我们有一堆。
AUDIENCE: I don't know what Crazy Eights is.
听众：我不知道什么是疯八。
PROFESSOR: We'll get to that.
教授：我们会解决的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
It's an 8.
是8。
AUDIENCE: I know what an 8 is, but I
听众：我知道8是什么，但是我
don't know how the game works.
不知道游戏如何运作。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
We'll get to it.
我们会解决的。
So, let's see.
所以，让我们看看。
4 of spades.
黑桃4。
OK, so this is a bunch of cards that
好，这是一堆卡片
were pulled out of the deck.
被从甲板上拉出来。
And we want the longest crazy subsequence.
我们想要最长的疯狂子序列。
And the crazy subsequence is a subsequence
疯狂的子序列是一个子序列
where two cards are like each other.
两张卡彼此相似的地方。
The way we define like is that either they
我们定义的方式是
have the same number.
具有相同的编号。
Or they have the same suit.
或者他们有同样的衣服。
Or one of them is an 8.
或其中之一是8。
So an 8 is like anything else.
所以8就像其他任何东西一样。
OK.
好。
So 4 and 8.
所以4和8。
Are they like each other?
他们彼此喜欢吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: 8 and 5.
教授：8和5。
Are they like each other?
他们彼此喜欢吗？
AUDIENCE: Yep.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
this 5, 5 of hearts and 9 of diamonds.
这5、5颗心和9颗钻石。
Are they like each other?
他们彼此喜欢吗？
No.
没有。
5 of hearts and 7 of hearts.
5心和7心。
Are they like each other?
他们彼此喜欢吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: 5 of spades and 7 of hearts, like each other?
教授：黑桃5和红心7，彼此喜欢吗？
No.
没有。
OK.
好。
So we have some cards that are like each other.
所以我们有一些彼此相似的卡片。
We want the longest possible subsequence.
我们想要最长的子序列。
AUDIENCE: What about 5 and 5?
听众：5和5怎么样？
Those are like each other.
那些彼此一样。
PROFESSOR: They're like each other, yep.
教授：是的，彼此一样。
They are more cards that are like each other than the ones
他们是比彼此更多相似的卡片
I drew here.
我在这里画
For example, this guy is like everything else.
例如，这个家伙就像其他一切一样。
Oh, we already drew that one.
哦，我们已经画了那个。
OK.
好。
So how do we model this problem using graphs?
那么我们如何使用图形对这个问题建模呢？
So, stuff that we knew before the last lecture.
因此，我们在上一堂课之前就知道了一些东西。
AUDIENCE: Those could all be nodes.
听众：这些全都是节点。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
All the cards are nodes.
所有卡都是节点。
That's good.
那很好。
And, I want the longest path between what and what?
而且，我想要什么和什么之间的最长路径？
AUDIENCE: One node to another?
听众：一个节点到另一个？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: The longest path in the graph.
受众：图形中的最长路径。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
The longest path in the graph.
图中的最长路径。
One trick to reduce it to a known problem
将其简化为已知问题的一个技巧
is to add the fake source.
是添加假货。
So this is a fake source.
因此，这是一个虚假来源。
And it's going to connect to everything.
并且它将连接到所有内容。
And this way, I want the longest path, starting from the source.
这样，我便希望从源头开始走最长的路。
AUDIENCE: And the other source?
听众：另一个来源？
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
The longest path, starting from the source, ending anywhere
最长的路径，从源头开始，到任何地方结束
in the graph.
在图中。
AUDIENCE: Such that it doesn't go touch another card again?
听众：这样就不会再碰另一张卡了吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So, if I want a longer subsequence,
所以，如果我想要更长的子序列，
that's a good question.
这是个好问题。
How would the edges look?
边缘看起来如何？
AUDIENCE: Directed.
听众：导演。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Directed.
导演。
And which direction?
哪个方向？
AUDIENCE: Arbitrary [INAUDIBLE].
听众：任意[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So, if I choose this one and this one,
教授：所以，如果我选择这个和这个，
can I go back afterwards?
我可以回去吗？
AUDIENCE: You just can't go back to the 4.
听众：您就是无法回到4。
PROFESSOR: So, in the longest common subsequence,
教授：因此，在最长的公共子序列中，
all the cards have to be in increasing order.
所有卡片必须按升序排列。
So I can say I'm going to choose this one, this one,
所以我可以说我要选择这个，这个，
and this one.
还有这个。
And they have to match in this order.
他们必须按此顺序进行匹配。
So I can only go forward.
所以我只能前进。
So I can't reorder the cards.
所以我不能重新排序卡。
My answer has to be, say, 4 of diamonds, 8 of diamonds.
我的答案必须是4颗钻石，8颗钻石。
And then, what else would match that?
然后，还有什么可以匹配的呢？
9 of diamonds.
9颗钻石。
AUDIENCE: You can put the 8 anywhere, though, right?
听众：不过您可以将8放在任何地方，对吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
I can't move them.
我不能动他们。
So the cards have to be in the initial order.
因此，卡片必须处于初始顺序。
I don't have to choose all the cards,
我不必选择所有卡片
but the cards that I choose have to respect
但是我选择的卡必须要尊重
the initial ordering.
初始订购。
AUDIENCE: So everything points right.
听众：所以一切都正确。
PROFESSOR: Everything points right.
教授：一切都正确。
Forward.
向前。
Yep.
是的
And, I need one more edge from here to here.
而且，从这里到这里，我还需要一个优势。
AUDIENCE: Oh, so you're saying in the game
听众：哦，所以你在游戏中说
you get an initial order.
您会收到初始订单。
And you can't reorder it.
而且您无法重新排序。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But otherwise I can, if I have all the cards,
但是如果我有所有的卡片，我可以
I'm just going to order them.
我要点菜。
AUDIENCE: Well, that's the point right?
听众：是的，对吗？
I was picturing more like you get a set of cards
我在想像更多像是你得到了一套卡片
and you try to figure out--
然后您尝试找出-
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
So, that's a different game.
因此，那是另一种游戏。
That might be harder to solve, so let's stick with this.
这可能很难解决，所以让我们坚持下去。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Why is 8 in there, with 7?
听众：为什么8个在里面，而7个在里面呢？
PROFESSOR: 8 is similar to anything.
教授：8类似于任何东西。
Just for the heck of it.
只是为了它。
These are the rules.
这些是规则。
OK, so we have a graph and we want
好，我们有一个图，我们想要
to compute the longest path.
计算最长路径。
We do not have an algorithm to compute the longest path.
我们没有算法来计算最长路径。
We only have algorithms to compute shortest paths.
我们只有用于计算最短路径的算法。
So how do I deal with that?
那么我该如何处理呢？
We had that in problem set six.
我们在第六个问题中遇到了问题。
AUDIENCE: Make all weights negative
观众：将所有权重设为负
because there's no cycle [INAUDIBLE].
因为没有周期[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
We know it's negative.
我们知道这是负面的。
And, I guess these ones don't matter.
而且，我猜这些都不重要。
But all these are going to be, instead of being 1,
但是所有这些将成为，而不是成为1
they're all going to be -1.
他们都将是-1。
Very good.
很好。
And there are no cycles in this graph,
此图中没有周期，
so we know that the answer will be well defined.
因此我们知道答案会很明确。
OK.
好。
Everyone with me so far?
到目前为止和我在一起的每个人？
Happy nods?
高兴点头？
Yes.
是。
So, what algorithm do I know that solves this problem?
那么，我知道哪种算法可以解决此问题？
AUDIENCE: Bellman-Ford.
听众：贝尔曼·福特。
PROFESSOR: Bellman-Ford.
教授：贝尔曼·福特。
Good.
好。
What is the running time of Bellman-Ford?
贝尔曼福特的运行时间是几点？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Suppose I have N cards.
假设我有N张卡。
How many vertices do I have?
我有多少个顶点？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Plus the source.
教授：再加上源代码。
It's ordering.
正在订购。
So you're right.
所以你是对的。
How many edges do I have?
我有多少条边？
Worst case.
最差的情况。
AUDIENCE: N squared.
听众：N平方。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] you mean, like, the directed [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：[听不清]你是说像导演[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: No, I mean Bellman-Ford.
教授：不，我是说贝尔曼·福特。
Then, we're going to go to that algorithm
然后，我们将转到该算法
and get the better running time.
并获得更好的运行时间。
AUDIENCE: Cause isn't Bellman-Ford e times e?
听众：是不是贝尔曼福特e倍e？
PROFESSOR: Oh.
教授：哦。
What?
什么？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, that's what I-- Did someone say, v plus e?
教授：是的，我就是-有人说v加e吗？
Or did I write v plus e?
还是我写了v加e？
Yep.
是的
You did.
你做到了
Thank you.
谢谢。
So it's v times e.
所以是e的v倍。
So the total running time is.
因此，总运行时间为。
aUDIENCE: N squared.
听众：N平方。
aUDIENCE: N cubed.
听众：N立方。
AUDIENCE: Or, n cubed.
听众：或者，n立方。
Yeah, it's multiplying [INAUDIBLE], too.
是的，它也乘以[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: You guys are mean today.
教授：你们今天很刻薄。
OK, so n cubed applying Bellman-Ford.
好的，因此可以应用Bellman-Ford。
There is a better way of solving this problem, right?
有解决这个问题的更好方法，对吗？
The Directed Acyclic Graph Bellman-Ford.
有向无环图Bellman-Ford。
So let's look at the Directed Acyclic Graph, not the one
因此，让我们看看有向无环图，而不是一个
to be generated by this because that might be a bit messy.
生成此文件，因为这可能有点混乱。
And let's try to compute shortest path.
让我们尝试计算最短路径。
s, a, b, c.
s，a，b，c。
OK, so let's see how we'd compute
好，让我们看看如何计算
the shortest path in this graph.
此图中最短的路径。
It's Acyclic, right?
它是非循环的，对不对？
All the the edges are pointing downwards.
所有的边缘都指向下方。
So let's try to compute them directly.
因此，让我们尝试直接计算它们。
I'm not going to write pseudocode first.
我不会先编写伪代码。
I'm going to write the formulas, and that
我要写公式，
will get the intuition for it.
会得到直觉的。
Then, maybe right psuedocode.
然后，也许是正确的伪代码。
So what is the distance from the source to itself?
那么，从源到自身的距离是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
The first ones are easy, so I'm going to do them myself.
第一个很简单，所以我要自己做。
sa is 1.
sa是1。
sb is 2.
sb是2。
sc is 3.
sc是3。
And, of course, you guys get to do the hard ones.
而且，当然，你们要努力去做。
So the distance from s to d is what?
那么从s到d的距离是多少？
How would I compute it?
我将如何计算？
AUDIENCE: There's two paths to get to [INAUDIBLE].
听众：有两种途径可以到达[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, I would want the shortest path from those, right?
所以，我想要最短的路径，对吧？
OK.
好。
So it's 4.
所以是4。
And the formula for it is the minimum of two paths, right?
它的公式是两条路径中的最小值，对吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] S to b, and then b to b.
听众：[听不清] S到b，然后b到b。
PROFESSOR: So, one path is--
教授：所以，一条路是-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] and s [? and b ?].
听众：[听不清]和s [？和b？]。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Wait.
教授：等等。
sa.
萨
So, first there's a path from s to a.
因此，首先存在从s到a的路径。
And the edge a to d.
和边缘a到d。
And then, there's a path from s to b.
然后，有一条从s到b的路径。
And the 8 from b to d, right?
从b到d的8对吧？
And I already know the values for sa and sb,
我已经知道sa和sb的值，
so this is well defined.
所以这是很好的定义。
We can compute it right away.
我们可以立即进行计算。
No recursion.
没有递归。
No metrics.
没有指标。
I mean, there's recursion, but there's no infinite recursion.
我的意思是，有递归，但没有无限递归。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
So, in order to get to d, there are two edges pointing into d.
因此，为了到达d，有两个指向d的边。
One of them coming from a.
其中之一来自。
One of them coming from b.
其中一个来自b。
So I can either get to a and take this edge.
所以我可以走到a并占据优势。
Or get to b and take this edge.
或到b并抓住这个优势。
This is what the formulas are saying.
这就是公式所说的。
How about se?s What's the formula?
SE怎么样？公式是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What are they?
这些是什么？
AUDIENCE: s3.
听众：s3。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, sa, sb, sc.
听众：是的，sa，sb，sc。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
Aed's.
艾德的
PROFESSOR: And the number?
教授：还有那个？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] 3?
听众：[听不清] 3？
I think.
我认为。
e to e.
从e到e。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
f.
F。
Someone that hasn't spoken today.
今天没有说话的人。
So that I can see that everyone gets it.
这样我就可以看到每个人都明白了。
Please.
请。
AUDIENCE: dsb--
观众：dsb--
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: --plus wef.
听众：-加上我们。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: And dsc plus wcf.
听众：还有dsc加wcf。
PROFESSOR: Awesome.
教授：太好了。
And that is--
那就是 -
PROFESSOR: 4.
教授：4。
PROFESSOR: I'll take your word for it.
教授：我会相信你的。
OK, so now the last one.
好，现在是最后一个。
Distance from std.
与标准距离。
AUDIENCE: 5.
听众：5。
Wait.
等待。
No.
没有。
PROFESSOR: So, let's write a formula.
教授：那么，让我们写一个公式。
AUDIENCE: Oh, g, not a.
听众：哦，克，不是。
AUDIENCE: That's 5.
听众：5。
AUDIENCE: 5.
PROFESSOR: OK, so let's write a formula
教授：好的，让我们写一个公式
to make sure that you guys are computing it
确保你们正在计算
in the fastest possible way for me.
以最快的方式对我来说。
So--
所以 -
sd plus sd to g.
SD加SD到g。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Does anyone else?
还有其他人吗？
Is this the only path?
这是唯一的途径吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
There's more.
还有更多。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Plus e as to f.
听众：对f加e。
PROFESSOR: Plus e as f.
教授：加e为f。
AUDIENCE: And n.
听众：而且。
AUDIENCE: c to f.
听众：c至f。
I mean, c to g.
我的意思是c到g。
Or, No. no.
或者，没有。
s to c.
s到c。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
See, there's a trick.
看，有个把戏。
OK.
好。
Cool.
凉。
And then, what are the weights?
然后，权重是多少？
AUDIENCE: w e to g.
听众：我们要克。
PROFESSOR: e to g.
教授：e至g。
Very good.
很好。
AUDIENCE: fg.
听众：fg。
PROFESSOR: fg.
教授：fg。
AUDIENCE: cg.
观众：cg。
PROFESSOR: cg.
教授：cg。
AUDIENCE: Why are you adding in c?
听众：为什么要添加c？
AUDIENCE: Because there's the extra c.
听众：因为还有多余的c。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I didn't see that.
听众：哦，我没看到。
PROFESSOR: So, the point of this guy's, is that if you do bfs,
教授：所以，这个家伙的意思是，如果您做bfs，
you'll get tricked.
你会被骗的。
Because bfs would put g on the same level as these.
因为bfs会将g置于与这些相同的级别。
And might compute the value for g
并可能计算g的值
before it has the values for these.
在拥有这些值之前。
OK, so what order do I need to compute these numbers in,
好的，所以我需要按什么顺序计算这些数字，
for this to work?
为了这个工作？
AUDIENCE: That way you computed them?
听众：以这种方式计算它们？
PROFESSOR: So, that is a, that is a, something of the graph.
教授：因此，这就是图中的某物。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Oh, topological.
听众：哦，拓扑。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Stole your answer.
偷了你的答案。
Topological sort.
拓扑排序。
So, any of the topological sorts works.
因此，任何拓扑排序都可以。
The one we used this time is sabcdefg.
我们这次使用的是sabcdefg。
Why am I using a topological sort?
为什么要使用拓扑排序？
AUDIENCE: Because there's dependency.
听众：因为有依赖性。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So, this depends on this and this, right?
所以，这取决于这个，对吧？
As c depends on sa, as b as c.
因为c取决于sa，所以b取决于c。
So basically, every edge here indicates a dependency.
因此，基本上，这里的每个边缘都表示依赖性。
In order to compute the shortest distance from the source
为了计算到源的最短距离
to here, I need to know the shortest
到这里，我需要知道最短的
distance from the source to these two.
从源到这两个的距离。
And then I can look at the edges.
然后我可以看看边缘。
So, the nice thing about a topological sort
因此，关于拓扑排序的好处
is, after I write the vertices this way,
就是这样写完顶点之后
all the edges point forward.
所有的边缘都指向前方。
Right? s to a. s to b.
对？到从s到b
s to c.
s到c。
a to d.
从a到d。
a to e.
从a到e
b to d.
b至d。
b to e.
从b到e。
b to f.
从b到f。
I can keep going.
我可以继续。
But the point is, there's no such thing as a backward edge.
但是关键是，没有后退之类的东西。
So if I compute the numbers in this order, when I get to se,
因此，如果我按此顺序计算数字，当我得出结论时，
I know that I computed the distance from s to abcd.
我知道我计算了从s到abcd的距离。
And if I have any edge coming into e,
如果我对e有任何优势，
I know that I've already computed the shortest distance
我知道我已经计算出最短距离
to the node that it is coming from.
到它来自的节点。
yes?
是？
Did I lose you guys?
我失去了你们吗？
Was this too--
也是吗？
AUDIENCE: So basically, like, at a,
听众：所以基本上，就像在
you relaxed all the edges going out of it.
您放松了所有的边缘。
PROFESSOR: You can look at it that way.
教授：您可以这样看。
But what we're doing here is I'm looking at a node
但是我们在这里要做的是我正在查看一个节点
and I'm relaxing all the edges coming into a node.
我正在放松进入节点的所有边缘。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: So this matches this order.
教授：所以这符合这个顺序。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: What you said doesn't match this order.
教授：您说的与这个命令不符。
But it's exactly the same thing.
但这是完全一样的。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: It'll give you the same result.
教授：它将为您带来相同的结果。
AUDIENCE: You'd get the first value at g when you reach c.
听众：达到c时，您将在g处获得第一个值。
But, like, end up with the same answer.
但是，最终得到相同的答案。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: We're still going backwards then, instead of--
听众：那时我们仍然倒退，而不是-
PROFESSOR: As long as you're processing the nodes
教授：只要您正在处理节点
in the topological sort order, all the algorithms
按照拓扑排序顺序，所有算法
will work because you're just computing
可以工作，因为您只是在计算
these terms in a different order.
这些术语以不同的顺序排列。
But as long as the dependencies are satisfied,
但是只要满足依赖关系
you're still going to get the right thing.
您仍然会得到正确的东西。
OK, so what's the running time of this?
好的，那么这是什么时间？
How many people know the running time
有多少人知道跑步时间
without having to write pseudocode for this?
不必为此编写伪代码？
I know the answer beforehand, so I cheated, obviously.
我事先知道答案，所以很明显我被骗了。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Is it a?
听众：是吗？
[INAUDIBLE] edges.
[听不清]边缘。
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
Very close.
很接近。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
PROFESSOR: So, it's the topological.
教授：这就是拓扑。
So, running time plus the running time
因此，运行时间加上运行时间
for evaluating this.
对此进行评估。
The running time for evaluating this is v plus e because you
评估它的运行时间是v加e，因为您
have every h shows up exactly once in here.
每个h都只在这里出现一次。
So you have e terms.
所以你有e条款。
And you have v vertices, even if you don't have any edge,
而且您有v个顶点，即使您没有任何边缘，
you have to initialize the verdicts.
您必须初始化判决。
So that's why it's v plus e.
这就是为什么它是v加e的原因。
AUDIENCE: It's also topological sort.
听众：这也是拓扑排序。
PROFESSOR: So, this is the order in which we process this.
教授：因此，这就是我们处理该问题的顺序。
So everything is v plus e.
所以一切都是v加e。
If we use this algorithm to solve this problem,
如果我们使用这种算法来解决这个问题，
what will the running time be?
运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
AUDIENCE: n squared.
听众：n平方。
AUDIENCE: It's an no.
听众：不可以。
PROFESSOR: So, it's v prime plus u prime, which
教授：所以，是v素数加上u素数，
is n squared plus [INAUDIBLE] squared, which is n squared.
是n平方加[音频不清]平方，即n平方。
So, by observing that this graph is acyclic,
因此，通过观察该图是非循环的，
we have a better running time than Bellman-Ford.
我们的运行时间比Bellman-Ford更好。
Even though we used exactly the same intuition
即使我们使用了完全相同的直觉
that we used up until now.
直到现在我们都用光了。
Model the problem as a graph.
将问题建模为图形。
Figure out what the edges are.
弄清楚边缘是什么。
Run a shortest path algorithm.
运行最短路径算法。
We have a better shortest path algorithm,
我们有一个更好的最短路径算法，
which works for Directed Acyclic Graphs,
适用于有向无环图，
so we get a better running time.
这样我们可以获得更好的运行时间。
OK, questions for what we did so far?
好，对我们到目前为止所做的事情有疑问吗？
AUDIENCE: It's [INAUDIBLE] on this graph here,
观众：这是这张图上的[音频不清晰]，
then you would do the same thing.
那么您将做同样的事情。
Take each node and then relax the incoming edges.
取每个节点，然后放宽传入的边缘。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So what is the topological sort of this?
那么，这种拓扑是什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: It's exactly the cards in the order
教授：这正是订单中的卡片
that they're on the board, right?
他们是董事会成员，对吗？
So, in dynamic programming, the topological sort order
因此，在动态编程中，拓扑排序顺序
is obvious.
很明显。
So the hard part is representing the state
所以最困难的部分是代表状态
and figuring out what the dependencies are.
并找出依赖项是什么。
So what the edges are.
那么边缘是什么。
And after that, the topological sort usually comes,
然后，通常会出现拓扑排序
it's fairly straightforward.
这很简单。
OK, so what we can do now, we have a few directions
好，所以我们现在可以做的，我们有几个指示
in which we can go.
在其中我们可以去。
We can write the pseudocode for this.
我们可以为此编写伪代码。
I mean, it's basically, it's just,
我的意思是，基本上就是
we're going to write abstract things instead of this.
我们将写抽象的东西代替这个。
So we're going to write one piece of pseudocode that
所以我们要编写一段伪代码
evaluates these.
评估这些。
So it's just generalizing this thing.
因此，只是概括了这一点。
Something else we can do is we can
我们可以做的其他事情就是
look at how would these things get computed using memoization?
看看如何使用记忆来计算这些东西？
We can look at how we would compute shortest path in graphs
我们可以看看如何计算图中的最短路径
with cycles.
与周期。
So this assumes we have a DAG.
因此，这假设我们有DAG。
What if we have cycles?
如果我们有周期怎么办？
How do we deal with them?
我们如何处理它们？
Or we can do another DP problem, and see how we'd model that.
或者，我们可以做另一个DP问题，然后看看如何建模。
So, votes?
那么，选票？
What do people want to see?
人们想看什么？
I think we might have time for two things, out of these four.
我认为我们可能有时间去做四件事中的两件事。
So, everyone votes for one.
因此，每个人都投一票。
And we'll start with that.
我们将从此开始。
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: DP problem.
听众：DP问题。
PROFESSOR: OK, so one vote for DP problem.
教授：好的，所以对DP问题投一票。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Cyclic.
听众：循环的。
AUDIENCE: Wait, you got two or one votes?
听众：等等，你有两票还是一票？
PROFESSOR: One vote.
教授：一票。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
I'll DP.
我去DP
AUDIENCE: I'll stick with [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我会坚持[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: DP.
听众：DP。
PROFESSOR: I think we're done here.
教授：我想我们已经完成了。
All right.
好吧。
So, new DP problem.
因此，新的DP问题。
So, suppose you have something like Manhattan's map, which
因此，假设您有类似曼哈顿的地图，
is basically a lattice.
基本上是一个格子。
Fancy math term for a grid.
网格的花式数学术语。
And suppose it we can only go forward and down.
并假设我们只能前进和后退。
So, all the streets are one way because they
所以，所有街道都是一种方式，因为它们
liked how people drive in San Francisco,
喜欢人们在旧金山开车的方式，
and decided they're going to do the same craziness.
并决定他们将做同样的疯狂。
So, we want to go from s to t.
因此，我们想从s转到t。
And there are different cost on all these edges.
所有这些优势都有不同的成本。
This is an n by m matrix.
这是一个n×m矩阵。
And I want to get from s to t in the shortest possible way.
我想以最短的时间从s到t。
So, let's model the problem.
因此，让我们对问题进行建模。
And then let's do recursion formulas
然后让我们做递归公式
and make it look like a DP instead of like a graph problem
并使它看起来像DP，而不是图问题
because-- it might be too easy of a graph
因为-绘制图形可能太容易了
problem in hindsight.
后见之明。
OK, so what's the graph problem?
好，那么图形问题是什么？
AUDIENCE: It's not equivalent.
听众：这不是对等的。
AUDIENCE: Topological sort.
听众：拓扑排序。
And then bfs.
然后是bfs。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Topological sort.
拓扑排序。
And then, and then that.
然后，然后那个。
Well, let's write this as, let's say
好吧，让我们这样写
that each node is so let's say that the nodes have numbers,
假设每个节点都有数字，
right?
对？
So this is 1,1 and this is 5,4.
所以这是1,1，这是5,4。
And I want to write this using math, so 2,1.
我想用数学写这个，所以2,1。
3,1.
3,1。
4,1.
4,1。
5,1.
5,1。
And then, 1,2.
然后是1,2。
1,3.
1,3。
1,4.
1,4。
OK, so this is the graph.
好，这是图形。
The shortest path from here to here is obvious.
从这里到这里的最短路径是显而易见的。
By the way, this is a real problem
顺便说一句，这是一个真正的问题
for people who don't see the connection
对于看不到联系的人
between dynamic programming and graphs.
在动态编程和图形之间。
I This problem has tripped up people on exams before.
我这个问题以前使人们跳入考试。
So it's not a toy problem.
因此，这不是玩具问题。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: So, on an examine, would you
听众：那么，从考核上，你会
have the option of just using a straight up graph algorithm--
可以选择仅使用向上图算法-
PROFESSOR: Well, we're going to ask you to solve this using DP.
教授：好吧，我们要请您使用DP解决此问题。
So let's try to solve this using dynamic programming by writing
因此，让我们尝试通过编写动态编程来解决此问题
recursion formulas.
递归公式。
So, what's the shortest distance to 1,1.
因此，到1,1的最短距离是多少。
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: OK, then.
教授：那好。
If I have a general distance, if I have some random node here,
如果我有一般距离，如果我在这里有一些随机节点，
dij, how do I compute this?
dij，我该如何计算？
AUDIENCE: It's a minimum distance
听众：这是最小距离
between the distance of law plus weights.
距离与重量之间的距离。
AUDIENCE: Or the distance of j.
听众：或j的距离。
i minus one.
我减一。
Yeah.
是的
PROFESSOR: So, i minus 1 j.
教授：所以我减去1 j。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
We get it.
我们知道了。
Plus the weight of the, yeah.
再加上重量，是的。
AUDIENCE: Going from one to the other.
听众：从一个到另一个。
PROFESSOR: OK, so the weight from i minus 1 j to ij.
教授：好的，所以权重从i减去1 j到ij。
OK.
好。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: j minus 1i.
听众：j减去1i。
For i, j minus 1.
对于i，j减1。
PROFESSOR: ij minus 1.
教授：ij减1。
AUDIENCE: Plus weight of that ij.
听众：加上那个ij的权重。
ij minus j1 to ij.
ij减去j1到ij。
ij [INAUDIBLE]
ij [听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So these are the recursions.
这些就是递归。
Now, how would I write the full set of code for this?
现在，我将如何为此编写完整的代码集？
So what's a valid topological sort for these guys?
那么，对于这些人来说，什么是有效的拓扑排序？
AUDIENCE: 1,1.
听众：1,1。
2,1.
2，1。
3,1.
3,1。
AUDIENCE: Dials.
听众：拨号。
AUDIENCE: 1,2.
观众：1,2。
AUDIENCE: The right dials.
听众：右拨盘。
PROFESSOR: That's going to be hard to code.
教授：这将很难编码。
That's going to be easy to code.
这将很容易编码。
So I'm going to take your answer.
因此，我将接受您的回答。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
AUDIENCE: What?
听众：什么？
PROFESSOR: I'm not going to take your answer because your answer
教授：我不会接你的答案，因为你的答案
is correct, but it's hard to code.
是正确的，但是很难编写代码。
AUDIENCE: But isn't that the same thing [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：但是[听不清]这不是一回事吗？
PROFESSOR: She says, go like this.
教授：她说，去吧。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
Oh.
哦。
PROFESSOR: So, here's how I'm going to code them.
教授：所以，这就是我要编码的方式。
4i in 1,2n.
1,2n中的4i。
4j in 1 to m.
4j in 1至m
So, I guess, first off, if i is 1 and j is 1, then d of ij
所以，我想，首先，如果i为1且j为1，则ij的d
is 0, right?
是0，对吗？
This is the base case.
这是基本情况。
Otherwise, d of ij equals big bad formula
否则，ij的d等于大坏公式
that we have up there.
我们在那里。
OK.
好。
Do we need anything else?
我们还需要其他东西吗？
AUDIENCE: DP.
听众：DP。
PROFESSOR: This is DP.
教授：这是DP。
We're done.
大功告成
AUDIENCE: Is it?
听众：是吗？
PROFESSOR: Almost work.
教授：差不多可以了。
Yeah, this is--
是的，这是-
AUDIENCE: Over [INAUDIBLE]--
听众：超过[听不清]-
AUDIENCE: I thought this was just programming.
听众：我以为这只是编程。
AUDIENCE: --it's a dictionary, though.
听众：-这是一本字典。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
It's programming.
它正在编程。
So this is the DP solution to the program
这是该程序的DP解决方案
because, instead of building the graph,
因为，与其建立图表，
you're writing the recursion.
您正在编写递归。
And you're writing using this implicit representation
您正在使用此隐式表示形式进行编写
of the graph.
图的
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: This is it.
教授：就是这样。
This is DP.
这是DP。
Most people are really afraid of it.
大多数人真的很害怕。
This is the hardest thing in the course.
这是课程中最难的事情。
If you get the connection between graphs and this,
如果您获得图与图之间的联系，
and if you know how to model graphs, that it.
如果您知道如何为图形建模，那就可以了。
You're one month in the term, you're
你任期一个月，你
done with six double six.
用六双六完成。
You already know everything to ace the exam.
您已经掌握了考试的所有条件。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Aren't graphs just programming, as well?
听众：不仅是图形，还是编程？
PROFESSOR: Ah.
教授：嗯。
But there, you're building a graph structure.
但是在那里，您正在构建一个图形结构。
Here, we don't need to build that structure.
在这里，我们不需要构建该结构。
Because we see the connection directly.
因为我们直接看到了连接。
Like, this code is much smaller, right?
就像，这段代码要小得多，对吧？
It's much easier to look at.
它看起来容易得多。
I mean, sorry.
我是说对不起
It's faster to read.
阅读起来更快。
But it looks like black magic if you
但是如果你看起来像黑魔法
don't see the underlying graph.
没有看到基础图。
Yes?
是？
Did you have a question?
你有问题吗
AUDIENCE: Yeah, so.
听众：是的。
What exactly is dynamic programming?
什么是动态编程？
Unless they give at least one or two examples of,
除非他们至少给出一个或两个例子，
like, using something that you had calculated already, or--
例如，使用您已经计算过的内容，或者-
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: --Fibinocci.
听众：--Fibinocci。
So.
所以。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So--
所以 -
AUDIENCE: Ah, so now you just have
听众：啊，所以现在你只有
to have a dictionary to store the minimum cost.
有字典来存储最低费用。
AUDIENCE: That's what d is, though.
听众：不过，这就是d。
The d of ij.
ij的d。
AUDIENCE: Wait.
听众：等等。
PROFESSOR: So.
教授：是的。
So I like your question.
所以我喜欢你的问题。
And I'm going to address all the other ones first.
我将首先解决所有其他问题。
And then I'm going to spend about five minutes
然后我要花大约五分钟
addressing your question.
解决您的问题。
What is dynamic programming, right?
什么是动态编程，对吗？
What is the point of this?
这有什么意义呢？
Like, what is dynamic programming?
就像什么是动态编程？
We're going to come back to this.
我们将回到这一点。
So any questions about this?
那么对此有任何疑问吗？
AUDIENCE: Wait.
听众：等等。
As you're going through--
当您经历-
AUDIENCE: Is there a dictionary?
听众：有字典吗？
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
This is an array.
这是一个数组。
Or dictionary.
或字典。
So, say this is ij.
所以，说这是ij。
If it's an array, or if it's a dictionary,
如果是数组或字典，
it would be d of the tuple ij.
这将是元组ij的d。
So, I can write this in Python, right?
所以，我可以用Python编写，对吧？
This is almost Python.
这几乎是Python。
What am I missing?
我想念什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE], or it fits inside.
观众：[听不清]，或适合里面。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
So, I have some boundary conditions, right?
所以，我有一些边界条件，对吗？
Because this guy would depend on this guy, which is inside.
因为这个家伙要依靠里面的那个家伙。
And left to depend on this guy.
并依靠这个家伙。
Which doesn't exist.
不存在。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
I wasn't-- OK.
我不是-好吧。
Sure.
当然。
PROFESSOR: So, we need a few more ifs here,
教授：所以，我们在这里还需要一些其他信息，
for boundary conditions.
边界条件。
AUDIENCE: I mean, in theory, though, you could just
听众：我是说，从理论上讲，你可以
run through the new dfs and create
运行新的dfs并创建
a topological of the source.
源的拓扑。
Right?
对？
And just run through that.
并通过运行。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But that's so much code to write.
但是，要编写的代码太多了。
Look at this.
看这个。
This is five lines.
这是五行。
AUDIENCE: Well, yeah.
听众：是的。
For this particular problem, it's five lines.
对于这个特定的问题，有五行内容。
PROFESSOR: Well, for dynamic programming,
教授：对于动态编程，
the solutions are 5 to 10 lines in general.
解决方案通常为5至10条生产线。
And the only hard thing in dynamic programming
而动态编程中唯一困难的事情
is figuring out what is the state going to be.
正在弄清楚状态将是什么。
So, after you get used to them, after you solve 10 or 20,
因此，当您习惯了它们之后，您解决了10或20个问题之后，
when people come out of programming contests,
当人们退出编程竞赛时，
and someone says, my solution's dynamic programming.
有人说，我的解决方案是动态编程。
Really?
真？
Wait, you can solve it that way.
等等，您可以通过这种方式解决。
And he says, yeah.
他说，是的。
This is the state.
这是状态。
And then everything else is obvious.
然后其他所有事情都是显而易见的。
Like, it's pretty easy to figure out everything else.
就像，找出其他所有内容很容易。
The hard part is the state.
困难的部分是状态。
So, it's enough to say my solution is
因此，足以说明我的解决方案是
dynamic programming.
动态编程。
This is my state.
这是我的状态。
You guys are probably going to have
你们可能会有
to say a bit more than that on the exam.
说的比考试还多。
But this is the hard part.
但这是困难的部分。
AUDIENCE: DP.
听众：DP。
PROFESSOR: No, you can't just say DP.
教授：不，您不能只说DP。
You'll definitely need at least a state.
您肯定至少需要一个状态。
OK.
好。
So.
所以。
AUDIENCE: You're also missing a state
听众：您还缺少状态
for deciding stuff in the dictionary, though, right?
决定字典中的内容，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Before deciding if my key is already
教授：在确定我的钥匙是否已经存在之前
in the dictionary?
在字典中？
Well, so, aside from the boundary conditions here,
好吧，除了这里的边界条件，
if I compute this here, it depends on theses two, right?
如果我在这里计算，那取决于这两个，对吗？
Are they going to be in the dictionary?
他们要去字典里吗？
AUDIENCE: Not yet.
听众：还没有。
PROFESSOR: Why?
教授：为什么？
If I'm running this way, so if I'm
如果我以这种方式运行，那么如果
computing all my values in this order.
按此顺序计算我的所有值。
So the first line one.
所以第一行。
Then line two.
然后第二行。
Then line three.
然后第三行。
They're already going to be in the dictionary.
他们已经在字典中了。
So this is because I'm doing topological sort.
这是因为我正在进行拓扑排序。
You don't need memoization if you're not
如果您不需要，则不需要记忆
using the topological sort of the graph.
使用图的拓扑排序。
You only need memoization if you don't.
如果不需要，则仅需要记忆。
AUDIENCE: So, why are we doing boundaries commissions if--
听众：那么，如果我们-
PROFESSOR: Because--
教授：因为-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So, I'm doing a boundary condition
教授：所以，我正在做一个边界条件
because if I paste this in if I paste this thing in, then when
因为如果我把它粘贴进去如果我把它粘贴进去
I am here, this is going to refer to this guy.
我在这里，这将是指这个家伙。
Which is fine.
没关系
But it's also going to refer to 2,0.
但这也将引用2,0。
Which doesn't exist.
不存在。
So the code might be a bit obfuscated by the boundary
所以代码可能会被边界混淆
conditions.
条件。
But it's 10 lines of code.
但这是10行代码。
It's pretty nice and straightforward.
这非常好，很直接。
OK, now what is dynamic programming?
好的，什么是动态编程？
I like that question.
我喜欢这个问题。
PROFESSOR: So, a key property, I don't
教授：所以，重要的财产
think it was mentioned in lecture.
认为这是在讲课中提到的。
Guys, correct me if I'm wrong.
伙计们，如果我错了，请纠正我。
It's called optimal substructure.
这称为最佳子结构。
Does that ring a bell?
那会响吗？
Probably going to hear about it next time, so.
大概下次会再听到。
Optimal substructure.
最佳子结构。
So, the point of optimal substructure
因此，最佳子结构的要点
is, suppose I have a shortest path from s to g.
是，假设我从s到g的路径最短。
Right?
对？
so, suppose I have shortest path from s to g.
因此，假设我从s到g的路径最短。
And that path is called p.
该路径称为p。
Now, suppose this path goes through d.
现在，假设此路径经过d。
So, path from s to g is actually s making a path through d.
因此，从s到g的路径实际上是s穿过d的路径。
And then there's another path going from d to g.
从d到g还有另一条路。
This path over here, p1.
这条路径在这里，p1。
p1 is guaranteed to be the shortest path, or a shortest
保证p1是最短路径或最短路径
path, from s to d.
从s到d的路径。
So this is the big solution.
所以这是个大解决方案。
It's optimal because we say it's the solution to the problem.
这是最佳选择，因为我们说这是解决问题的方法。
This is a part of the solution.
这是解决方案的一部分。
This part of the solution is optimal for this part
解决方案的这一部分对此部分是最佳的
of the problem.
问题。
So the part of the problem is getting from s to d.
因此，问题的一部分是从s到d。
The part of the big optimal solution
最佳解决方案的一部分
is optimal-- so the small part of the big solution
是最佳的-所以大解决方案的一小部分
is optimal with respect to the small problem.
就小问题而言，最佳。
So p1 has to be a shortest path from s to d.
因此p1必须是从s到d的最短路径。
Do you guys want to see a proof by contradiction?
你们想看到矛盾的证据吗？
Or do take my word for it?
还是相信我的话？
Does anyone want to?
有人要吗？
So, intuitively, the idea is that if you had the better
因此，从直觉上讲，想法是，如果您有更好的
path here, say that path would be s3,
这里的路径，说路径将是s3，
then I could replace this, sorry. p3.
那我可以代替它，对不起。 p3。
I could replace this with p3.
我可以将其替换为p3。
And I would have a better path overall.
总体而言，我会有一条更好的道路。
And that would contradict the fact
这与事实相反
that this is the best path.
这是最好的道路。
So this part of the path has to be a shortest path
所以这部分路径必须是最短的路径
to get from s to d.
从s到d。
So I've broken up my problem to get from s to g,
所以我把问题分解成从s到g，
into saying, I want to get from s to d, from s to e.
说，我想从s到d，从s到e。
Or, from s to f and then cross one edge.
或者，从s到f，然后越过一条边。
And then the ways I get from s to d from s to e, or from s
然后我从s到d从s到e或从s的方法
to f, have to be optimal.
到f，必须是最优的。
I've already encoded that here.
我已经在这里编码了。
And nobody asked me, yo, is this true?
没有人问我，哟，这是真的吗？
Can I take a longer path here?
我可以在这里走更长的路吗？
And have a better solution?
有更好的解决方案吗？
The answer is no.
答案是不。
In some problems, the answer is yes.
在某些问题上，答案是肯定的。
Those are not problems that you can
这些不是您可以解决的问题
solve with dynamic programming.
用动态编程解决。
if, in your problems, that's the case,
如果是这种情况，
you probably forgot to account for some part of the state.
您可能忘记了占州的一部分。
AUDIENCE: What kind of problems would it
听众：会出现什么样的问题
be where that wouldn't be true?
在那不是真的吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, remember the quiz problem
教授：好吧，请记住测验问题
with the gas stations?
加油站？
If you don't account for the gas, if you do Dijkstra, then,
如果您不考虑汽油费用，那么如果您选择Dijkstra，那么，
well.
好。
Guess what?
你猜怎么了？
Shortest path in the graph, if that
图形中的最短路径（如果这样）
doesn't account for gas stops, if you start accounting
如果您开始核算，则不代表加油站
for the cost of refilling, this path
为了加油的成本，这条路
might be longer than a path that goes like this.
可能比这样的路径更长。
So, it's longer in terms of road stalls.
因此，在道路失速方面更长。
But has fewer, or has cheaper, gas stations on the way.
但途中加油站的数量较少，或更便宜。
So then, there's no optimal substructure.
因此，就没有最佳的子结构。
And that's because you didn't account for the fuel states.
那是因为您没有考虑燃油状态。
OK.
好。
Probably not the best example.
可能不是最好的例子。
Sorry for bringing up painful memories.
很抱歉带来痛苦的回忆。
But the point is, usually when you
但是关键是，通常当你
have this with our problems, you didn't account for the state.
遇到我们的问题时，您并没有说明状态。
All the problems that are solved with dynamic programming
动态编程解决的所有问题
have this thing called optimal substructure.
这个东西叫做最优子结构。
And this is sort of how it works.
这就是它的工作方式。
OK.
好。
I have no idea how much time I have because my phone crashed.
我不知道有多少时间，因为手机坏了。
So can anyone help me?
有人可以帮我吗？
Five minutes.
5分钟。
10 minutes.
10分钟。
Sorry.
抱歉。
AUDIENCE: Seven minutes.
听众：七分钟。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What else do you guys want to see?
你们还想看到什么？
AUDIENCE: Cycles.
听众：循环。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Is everyone happy with cycles?
每个人都对周期感到满意吗？
OK.
好。
Almost everyone, so that's good enough.
几乎所有人，这样就足够了。
OK.
好。
Let's do cycles.
让我们做循环。
We have seven minutes.
我们有七分钟。
So, suppose I have this graph.
所以，假设我有这张图。
Source going a going to be going to c.
源将要去c。
And then the costs are 1 minus 1.
则成本为1减去1。
1.
1。
Can I solve it using that method?
我可以用那种方法解决吗？
Probably not.
可能不是。
Let's try to write the recursions
让我们尝试编写递归
to see what we get for the formulas.
看看我们从公式中得到什么。
So, dsa is--
因此，dsa是-
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: --minimum.
教授：-最少。
Yeah, it's 1.
是的，是1。
But it's the minimum of dss plus weight sa.
但这是dss加权重sa的最小值。
ds-- well, almost.
ds-好吧，差不多。
Actually, it's not 1.
其实不是1。
Likely.
有可能
You're confusing me again.
你又让我迷惑了。
There's one more edges that they have to account for.
他们还需要考虑更多的优势。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: dsc plus weight.
教授：DSC加重量。
I'm going to fail today.
我今天会失败。
I'm tired.
我累了。
AUDIENCE: ca.
观众：
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we accounted for both edges coming in now.
因此，我们考虑了现在出现的两个方面。
dsb is minimum of dsa plus weight ab.
dsb是dsa加上权重ab的最小值。
dsc is minimum of dsb plus weight bc.
dsc是dsb加上权重bc的最小值。
Right?
对？
And dss is 0 because we promised that's how we start.
dss为0，因为我们保证这就是开始的方式。
OK.
好。
Now what if I try evaluate these?
现在，如果我尝试评估这些怎么办？
Is there a sane order in which I can evaluate them?
我可以以合理的顺序评估它们吗？
Nope.
不。
Let's see why.
让我们看看为什么。
If I try to evaluate sa, this depends on sc.
如果我尝试评估sa，则取决于sc。
AUDIENCE: Which we don't have yet.
听众：我们还没有。
PROFESSOR: sc is here. sc depends on sb.
教授：sc在这里。 sc取决于sb。
sb is here.
某人在这里。
And it depends on sa.
这取决于sa。
Which was.
是的
So we have this infinite recursion, right?
所以我们有这个无限递归，对吗？
They all depend on each other.
他们彼此依赖。
There's a loop here.
这里有一个循环。
There's a negative cycle.
有一个负面的周期。
Can't use this algorithm.
无法使用此算法。
That's a shame.
真可惜
What can we do instead?
我们该怎么办呢？
PROFESSOR: Show a negative node.
教授：显示一个负节点。
A negative weight.
负重。
half.
半。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: Can we just get rid of the negative weight half?
听众：我们能摆脱负重的一半吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
That's the best edge.
那是最好的优势。
That's probably going to be part of the solution, right?
那可能是解决方案的一部分，对吧？
AUDIENCE: Can we add 1 to all the edges?
听众：我们可以在所有边上加1吗？
PROFESSOR: That's still going to have a cycle.
教授：那仍然会有一个周期。
I still won't be able to run this.
我仍然无法运行该程序。
AUDIENCE: Oh, yeah.
听众：哦，是的。
AUDIENCE: Bellman-Ford.
听众：贝尔曼·福特。
PROFESSOR: Bellman-ford.
教授：贝尔曼福德。
AUDIENCE: That's not dynamic.
听众：这不是动态的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Well, one way to do it is Bellman-Ford, right?
好吧，贝尔曼-福特（Bellman-Ford）就是其中一种，对吗？
Another way, which we went through last time,
我们上次经历的另一种方式，
is to break the cycle.
是打破周期。
And the way we break the cycle is we
我们打破周期的方式是
add the path length into the equation.
在等式中添加路径长度。
So, I'm going to look at the distance
所以，我要看看距离
from a source to some node, so the distance
从源到某个节点的距离
from a source to some node, as the distance from the source
从源到某个节点的距离，即到源的距离
to some other node plus the edge weight.
到其他节点再加上边缘权重
This is what I had before, right?
这是我以前的经历，对吧？
Nothing new here.
这里没有新内容。
So dsv is the minimum over all the edges of dsu
所以dsv是dsu所有边缘的最小值
plus weight uv, Right?
再加上紫外线，对吗？
Minimum over all uv.
最低的所有紫外线。
That's our edges.
那就是我们的优势。
Right?
对？
This is the old stuff.
这是旧的东西。
Now, we're going to say this instead.
现在，我们将改为这样说。
The distance from s to v, using a path of length k,
s到v的距离，使用长度为k的路径，
is the minimum over all the edges of the distance from s
是距s的距离的所有边的最小值
to u, using a path of what length?
到您，使用什么长度的路径？
If this path is length k.
如果此路径的长度为k。
So k edges.
所以k条边。
How many edges do I have here?
我这里有几个边？
AUDIENCE: k equals 1.
听众：k等于1。
PROFESSOR: So this is distance su using k minus 1
教授：这是使用s减去1的距离su
plus the weight of uv.
再加上紫外线的重量。
AUDIENCE: So what's the difference between the two?
听众：两者之间有什么区别？
PROFESSOR: So, this will always decrease.
教授：因此，这将永远减少。
So I guarantee that they will not have an infinite recursion.
因此，我保证它们不会有无限递归。
This is the magic that makes it work.
这就是使它起作用的魔力。
Now, an equivalent way of looking at this,
现在，以一种等效的方式来看待这一点，
is building a graph.
正在建立图表。
That's what we've been doing so far.
到目前为止，这就是我们一直在做的事情。
So let's build an equivalent graph to this.
因此，让我们为此构建一个等效图。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: It's going to get to 0 eventually, right?
教授：最终将变为0，对吗？
So when k is 0, the distance from the source to itself is 0.
因此，当k为0时，从源到自身的距离为0。
But the distance from the source to any other nodes is infinity.
但是从源到任何其他节点的距离都是无穷大。
Because from the source, we can't
因为从源头上讲，我们不能
get to anywhere else in 0 edges.
到达0边的其他任何地方。
We can't teleport.
我们不能传送。
So let's build a graph to get the intuition for this.
因此，让我们建立一个图表来获得直觉。
This looks mathy.
这看起来很数学。
This looks too mathy.
这看起来太数学了。
So, at the first layer, you only have the source.
因此，在第一层，您只有源。
You can only get from the source to itself
您只能从源头获取自身
by not crossing any edges.
不跨越任何边缘。
At level one, you potentially have all the nodes.
在第一级，您可能拥有所有节点。
If the source is connected to everything,
如果源连接到一切，
you might have all the nodes.
您可能拥有所有节点。
So, s1, a1, b1, c1.
因此，s1，a1，b1，c1。
Where can you get from the source?
您可以从哪里获得信息？
AUDIENCE: To a.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: To a.
教授：要
What's the cost of the edge?
优势成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Now, let's build a second layer.
现在，让我们构建第二层。
s2, a2, b2, c2.
s2，a2，b2，c2。
So someone tell me the edges.
所以有人告诉我边缘。
So, assuming I can get to this node using one
因此，假设我可以使用一个
edge, how can I get to this other node using two edges?
边缘，如何使用两个边缘到达另一个节点？
AUDIENCE: A to b.
听众：从A到b。
PROFESSOR: OK. a to b.
教授：好的。从a到b。
a1 to b2.
a1至b2。
AUDIENCE: 2.
听众：2。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Cost?
成本？
AUDIENCE: 1 [INAUDIBLE].
观众：1 [听不清]。
A1 to c--
A1至c--
AUDIENCE: That's negative 1.
听众：这是负面的1。
PROFESSOR: a1 to b2.
教授：a1至b2。
Thank you.
谢谢。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: Are we doing anything else?
听众：我们还有其他事情吗？
PROFESSOR: I think so.
教授：我是这样认为的。
So, if I'm at b using one edge, I can get to c using two edges.
因此，如果我使用一条边在b处，则可以使用两条边到达c。
Cost?
成本？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
If I'm at c using one edge--
如果我在c上使用一条边线-
AUDIENCE: a.
听众：a。
PROFESSOR: --using two edges.
教授：-使用两个边缘。
Cost?
成本？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And if I'm at s using one edge?
如果我在使用一条边？
AUDIENCE: a.
听众：a。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Can you?
教授：可以吗？
AUDIENCE: There's now edge.
听众：现在有优势。
PROFESSOR: There's no edge.
教授：没有优势。
AUDIENCE: I thought it was just like an assumed edge.
听众：我认为这就像一个假定的优势。
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
Nope.
不。
Not an edge.
不是优势。
As to a, cost?
至于，费用？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: 1.
教授：1。
OK.
好。
Let's build a third level.
让我们建立第三个层次。
s3, a3, b3, c3.
s3，a3，b3，c3。
Someone dictate the edges please.
请有人指示边缘。
AUDIENCE: S2 to a3.
听众：S2到a3。
With 1.
用1。
I mean, it's going to be the exact same.
我的意思是，它将完全相同。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
a2 to b3 minus 1.
a2至b3减1。
b2 to c3 1.
b2至c3 1。
And c2 to a3 1.
和c2到a3 1。
So these are exactly the same edges, right?
所以这些边完全一样，对不对？
Because they're the original edges in the graph.
因为它们是图形中的原始边缘。
Every edge in the graph can connect to levels here.
图中的每个边都可以连接到此处的层。
So, all edges.
因此，所有边缘。
All edges.
所有边缘。
All edges from s.
s的所有边。
How many layers do I need?
我需要几层？
AUDIENCE: e.
听众：e。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Pretty close.
八九不离十。
Let's try something smaller.
让我们尝试一些较小的东西。
AUDIENCE: a.
听众：a。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
That makes no sense.
这是没有意义的。
PROFESSOR: So, what's the longest path in a graph?
教授：那么，图中的最长路径是什么？
Graph of v vertices.
v个顶点的图形。
What is the longest path?
最长的路是什么？
AUDIENCE: The number [INAUDIBLE].
听众：数字[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: The longest shortest path.
教授：最长最短的路径。
AUDIENCE: v minus 1.
听众：v减1。
PROFESSOR: v minus 1.
教授：v减1。
That's how Bellman-Ford has v minus 1 runs, right?
这就是Bellman-Ford v减1的方式，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: So, a shortest path can't have a cycle.
教授：因此，最短的路径不能有循环。
If it has a cycle, then it means it's an infinite cycle.
如果有一个循环，则意味着这是一个无限循环。
So there's no solution.
因此，没有解决方案。
Shortest paths have no cycles therefore,
因此，最短路径没有循环，
even if they go through the entire graph,
即使他们遍历整个图表，
they're going to have v minus 1 edges.
他们将有v减去1个边。
So I'm going to have v minus 1 layers.
因此，我将拥有v减去1层。
Here, I drew three layers, so I'm done.
在这里，我画了三层，到此为止。
That's why I stopped at three.
这就是为什么我三点停下来。
So let's see how many nodes and how many edges we're
让我们来看看我们有多少个节点和多少个边缘
going to have if we do this transformation.
如果我们进行这种转换，将会有。
v prime is-- so, how many times am I going to copy the graph?
v素数是-那么，我要复制多少次图表？
AUDIENCE: Two or thee times.
听众：两次或两次。
AUDIENCE: Three times.
听众：三遍。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And in general terms?
一般而言？
AUDIENCE: v minus 1.
听众：v减1。
AUDIENCE: v minus 1 times.
听众：v减1倍。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So I'm going to copy the graph v minus 1 times.
因此，我将复制图v减1次。
And then I'm going to add that one source, right?
然后我要添加一个来源，对吗？
Doesn't really matter because it's order of b squared.
并不重要，因为它是b的平方。
How many edges?
有多少条边？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Order of v times e.
教授：v乘以e的顺序。
We can do the math that's whatever.
我们可以做任何数学运算。
Let's say it's something like this.
假设是这样的。
So the running time-- this graph is acyclic, right?
所以运行时间-此图是非循环的，对不对？
All the nodes are going forward.
所有节点都在前进。
The new graph that I have here.
我在这里的新图。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So, I can use the DAG algorithm.
教授：因此，我可以使用DAG算法。
So the running time, if I use the DAG algorithm,
所以运行时间，如果我使用DAG算法，
is v prime plus e prime.
是v素数加上e素数。
Which is?
哪一个
AUDIENCE: v.
听众：v。
PROFESSOR: Thank you.
教授：谢谢。
AUDIENCE: Or is it ve?
听众：或者是ve？
PROFESSOR: So, it's v squared plus ve, which is ve,
教授：所以，它是v平方加ve，即ve，
for most purposes.
对于大多数目的。
And this is?
这是吗？
AUDIENCE: Bellman-Ford.
听众：贝尔曼·福特。
PROFESSOR: Bellman-Ford.
教授：贝尔曼·福特。
So this is Bellman-Ford.
这就是贝尔曼福特。
This is what Bellman-Ford does.
这就是贝尔曼·福特所做的。
Except when you're coding it up, it
除非您要对其进行编码，
relaxes the edges in a different way.
以另一种方式放松边缘。
But this is the intuition behind Bellman-Ford.
但这是贝尔曼福特背后的直觉。
And this is an easy way to see why Bellman-Ford works.
这是了解Bellman-Ford工作原理的简便方法。
AUDIENCE: So, practically, we really
听众：所以，实际上，我们真的
wouldn't want to do dynamic programming.
不想做动态编程。
We just want to run Bellman-Ford because that's
我们只想运行Bellman-Ford，因为那是
less code, right?
更少的代码，对不对？
PROFESSOR: So, this is the dynamic programming
教授：这就是动态编程
view of Bellman-Ford.
曼-福特的鸟瞰图。
Write Bellman-Ford.
写贝尔曼福特。
There's a reason why we taught you to write it that way.
我们教会您以这种方式编写它是有原因的。
It's going to be shorter.
它会更短。
This just gives you more intuition.
这只是给您更多的直觉。
And it shows you how the DAG algorithm
并向您展示DAG算法
relates to Bellman-Ford.
与Bellman-Ford有关。
And this is how we handle cycles, which are removed.
这就是我们处理循环的方式，这些循环被删除了。
So, that means I have fulfilled my promise of covering
所以，这意味着我已经兑现了我的承诺
two of the issues that I had on the board.
我在董事会上遇到的两个问题。
Yes.
是。
So any questions about this?
那么对此有任何疑问吗？
So, we didn't do the pseudocode for the shortest
所以，我们没有做最短的伪代码
path using DAGs.
使用DAG的路径。
The code that we gave you in the code handout
我们在代码讲义中提供给您的代码
matches the pseudocode that you'd write.
与您编写的伪代码匹配。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So, if all edges were negative 1 here,
听众：所以，如果所有边都为负1，
except for the top edge, looking at this graph over here,
除了顶部边缘，在这里看这张图，
how would the search go through, such that it would find,
搜索将如何进行，以便能够找到，
lik,e negative two weight half?
好吧，负二重一半？
PROFESSOR: So these edges are minus 1?
教授：那么这些边是负1？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Well, do you have a solution in this case?
教授：好吧，在这种情况下，您有解决方案吗？
AUDIENCE: It's no.
听众：不是。
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
But you could have this, right?
但是你可以有这个吧？
And expect the whole thing to work.
并期望整个工作正常。
AUDIENCE: No, that's still not, that's not making sense.
听众：不，那不是，那没有道理。
PROFESSOR: Is it?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: It's negative 1 cycle.
听众：这是负1个周期。
PROFESSOR: Oh, yeah.
教授：哦，是的。
That's unfortunate.
那真不幸。
OK.
好。
Never mind.
没关系。
Do like this?
喜欢这个吗
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: So, also, looking at the graph,
听众：同样，从图表来看，
there's only one natural path that you can take.
您只能采取一种自然的方法。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So, if I go from s to c, like this, sabc,
因此，如果我像这样从s转到c，
this is going to be s0, a1, b2, c3.
这将是s0，a1，b2，c3。
So, all the paths go ahead.
因此，所有的道路都是前进的。
AUDIENCE: So, what if I wanted to find the shortest
听众：所以，如果我想找到最短的
path to s to b?
s到b的路径？
Like, in terms of actually writing an algorithm,
就实际编写算法而言，
would it be s0, a1, b2, or s1?
是s0，a1，b2还是s1？
a2, b3.
a2，b3。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, if you actually want to read the shortest path,
因此，如果您实际上想读取最短路径，
then the shortest path could have length 1, length 2,
那么最短路径的长度可能为1，长度为2
or length 3, right?
或长度3，对不对？
I don't know.
我不知道。
So I would have to look at all these.
所以我将不得不看所有这些。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
OK.
好。
So you just run it from s0 to any b, basically.
因此，基本上，您只需将其从s0运行到任意b。
PROFESSOR: So, the algorithm that we have there computes
教授：所以，我们在那里计算的算法
the path from one source to everything else.
从一种来源到其他一切的路径。
So I run it.
所以我运行它。
It runs.
它运行。
Computes all the shortest paths.
计算所有最短路径。
And then I have to read these ones.
然后，我必须阅读这些内容。
And get the smallest one.
并得到最小的。
That's a question.
这是一个问题。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Yeah, that is a detail that I left out.
是的，这是我遗漏的细节。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So, no more cycles.
因此，不再需要任何周期。
OK.
好。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: I'm still, like, on the initial problem and stuff.
听众：我仍然喜欢最初的问题。
A bit of a disconnect.
有点断开。
When you were underlining stuff, like the sa,
当您强调诸如sa之类的内容时，
it seemed to me that, like, in that case,
在我看来，在那种情况下，
when you're going forward, you're never
当你前进时，你永远不会
going to stop because you're doing recursion.
将停止，因为您正在执行递归。
So you never have a beginning point, almost.
因此，几乎没有一个起点。
Effectively, if you, like--
实际上，如果您喜欢-
PROFESSOR: So, do you mean here?
教授：那么，您的意思是这里吗？
AUDIENCE: Well, yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So, in that case, this is the beginning point.
教授：那么，这就是起点。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: If I go through the nodes in the topological sort
教授：如果我按照拓扑顺序遍历节点
order, then all I need is one beginning point.
订单，那么我所需要的只是一个起点。
Because everything else will refer back to that.
因为其他所有内容都会参考该内容。
There has to be a topological sort order.
必须有一个拓扑排序顺序。
And the first node in that order is my source.
依次排列的第一个节点是我的来源。
And, if we have cycles, then the beginning conditions are here.
而且，如果我们有周期，那么开始条件就在这里。
So that's why I'm only drawing this vertex.
这就是为什么我只绘制此顶点。
Because these other vertices wouldn't be useful.
因为这些其他顶点将无用。
OK.
好。
So then, that being said, don't forget your quizzes and happy
因此，话虽这么说，别忘了测验和快乐
Thanksgiving.
感恩。